<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<post>
		<ID>1035</ID>
		<Slug>guest-lecture-on-software-engineering-insights</Slug>
		<Title><![CDATA[Guest lecture on 'Software Engineering Insights']]></Title>
		<Date>2011-04-25</Date>
		<Status>publish</Status>
		<Categories>Programming</Categories>
		<Tags>software</Tags>
		<Content><![CDATA[<p>A month or two back I was contacted by <a href="http://wbillingsley.blogspot.com/">Will Billingsley</a>, a lecturer at the <a href="http://www.uq.edu.au">University of Queensland</a> (which I happen to live pretty much over the river from). I met him at JavaOne 2010, given his interest in JavaFX. He asked me if I'd like to give a guest lecture to a class of third-year software students (specifically, <a href="http://itee.uq.edu.au/~csse3002/">CSSE3002 The Software Process</a>). All up there was somewhere between 50 and 80 students, so it was a far bigger turnout than I expected (especially compared to back when I was in third-year a few years back). To quote Will's initial email to me:</p>
<p><p style="padding-left: 30px;">"Essentially we invite people from industry to pass on to students their  wisdom and experience from producing software commercially. &nbsp;The title  for those talks this year is "how is software engineering more than just  design, code, and test" - but you needn't feel constrained by that --  most guests use it as a segue into what they'd really like to talk  about."</p>
<p><p style="padding-left: 30px;">"I thought you might be an ideal person to give a talk as your experience  working in distributed teams, working on a product where the customers  are other developers, and working on a team that's survived changes in  company strategy and ownership, would give you very valuable insights to  pass on."</p>
<p>I thought I was totally unqualified to give a talk, so I tried to push back, but Will convinced me. I decided to cover the lecture topic directly - I had nothing to sell or segue in to. Therefore, this was the first talk I've done in a <em>really</em> long time that didn't have any code in it, which felt rather odd. Unfortunately, given how busy I am with my day job, I didn't have a great deal of time to actually create a decent slide deck. I basically threw up a bunch of bullet points, and expanded on each slide over the hour or so my talk went for. I actually had enough content to cover another hours worth of topics, but I knew I wouldn't have time to cover everything, so this is all I presented. Totally bad presentation-foo, but it's the best I could do.</p>

<p>I doubt there will be much interest in the slides from most visitors to this site, but I thought for the sake of the students that I presented to that <a href="/downloads/presentations/2011/04/UQ-talk-April-2011.pdf">I'd post up a PDF of the slides here</a>.</p>

<p>I hope in general that most other software engineers, who decide to read these slides, can agree with what I say. The suggestions are based on my experience - but I invite others to leave comments with their own suggestions and/or suggestions on where I'm wrong.</p>
]]></Content>
	</post>
