<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<post>
		<ID>1222</ID>
		<Slug>java-desktop-links-of-the-week-april-3</Slug>
		<Title>Java desktop links of the week, April 3</Title>
		<Date>2012-04-03</Date>
		<Status>publish</Status>
		<Categories><![CDATA[Programming>Java>Java Client]]></Categories>
		<Tags/>
		<Content><![CDATA[<p>Hello everyone! This is <a href="http://fxexperience.com/2012/03/interview-with-carl-dea/">Carl Dea</a> (<a href="http://twitter.com/carldea">@carldea</a>) and I am filling in for <strong>Jonathan</strong> who is currently at <a href="http://www.oracle.com/javaone/jp-ja/english-1481916-ja.html">JavaOne</a> in Tokyo, Japan. This has been a busy week in the JavaFX community. Here are this week links.</p>

<p>(Note from <strong>Jonathan</strong>: Thanks to <strong>Carl</strong> for stepping up to the plate for this week and next week. <a href="http://www.apress.com/9781430242574">You really should consider buying his book</a>).</p>
<h4>JavaFX</h4>
<ul>
	<li><a href="http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/java/javafx/downloads/devpreview-1429449.html">JavaFX 2.1 build b19</a> Developer Preview Download is available!</li>
	<li><strong>Stephen Chin</strong> has released his slide presentations from the 33rd Degree Conference. One of the slide presentations discusses developing JavaFX 2.x applications using the <a href="http://www.scala-lang.org/">Scala</a> language titled "<a href="http://www.slideshare.net/steveonjava/javafx-2-and-scala-like-milk-and-cookies-33rd-degrees">JavaFX 2 and Scala - Like Milk and Cookies</a>". The other slide presentation covers the development of <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/steveonjava/cleaner-apis-cleaner-uis-with-visage-33rd-degrees">cleaner APIs and better UIs</a> on the JavaFX 2.x platform using the <a href="http://code.google.com/p/visage/">Visage</a> language.</li>
	<li>(Late breaking link from <strong>Jonathan</strong>): Speaking of <strong>Stephen</strong> and <strong>Jim</strong>, they have just announced that they are joining the <a href="https://blogs.oracle.com/java/entry/two_javafx_community_rock_stars?utm_source=twitterfeed&amp;utm_medium=twitter">Java envangelism team at <del>NASA</del> Oracle</a>. <strong>Stephen</strong> has blogged about this <a href="http://javafx.steveonjava.com/joining-nasa-to-conquer-space-with-java/">both on</a>, and <a href="http://steveonjava.com/oracle-propels-javafx-forward-by-enlisting-weaver-and-chin/">fortunately after</a>, April Fools Day. I've got an interview lined up with them that I'll publish over at FX Experience in the coming weeks.</li>
	<li><strong>Chika Okereke</strong> has blogged about a <a href="http://www.jpedal.org/PDFblog/2012/03/pdf-to-javafxml-conversion-creating-a-javafxml-application-with-netbeans-adding-buttons/">PDF to JavaFXML conversion</a> using a technique which applies CSS styles to JavaFX 2.x graph nodes dynamically using the @FXML annotation.</li>
	<li><strong>Bertrand Goetzmann</strong> has shown off a screen cast demonstrating an application he is working on called <a href="http://www.screenr.com/PKU8">Metaphora</a> (<a href="https://bitbucket.org/account/signin/?next=/bgoetzmann/metaphora/wiki/Home">source code</a>). He has made use of <a href="http://groovy.codehaus.org/GroovyFX">GroovyFX</a> and <a href="http://www.jboss.org/netty">Netty</a> which are two powerful combinations (A graphics DSL handling file transfers with non blocking I/O).</li>
	<li><strong>Jonathan Giles</strong> has continued with his series of interviews with key software engineers at Oracle. Jonathan has interviewed <a href="http://fxexperience.com/2012/03/interview-with-jeff-hoffman/"><strong>Jeff Hoffman</strong></a> and <a href="http://fxexperience.com/2012/03/interview-with-david-grieve/"><strong>David Grieve</strong></a>. Jeff is a lead user experience developer who has the very huge responsibility of the end-to-end deployment experience. David is an engineer on the UI controls team who is (a hero imo) behind JavaFX’s CSS support. :)</li>
	<li><a href="https://blogs.oracle.com/javaspotlight/entry/java_spotlight_episode_76_pro">The Java Spotlight episode 76 podcast</a> has interviewed authors <strong>James Weaver , Weiqi Gao , Stephen Chin , Dean Iverson, and Johan Vos</strong> (The Dream Team) to talk about their recently published book, <a href="http://www.apress.com/9781430268727">Pro JavaFX 2</a>. This interview highlighted separate areas of the book which were crafted by each individual author’s unique expertise.</li>
	<li>Also, at Java.net <strong>Johan Vos</strong> explains about ways to handle <a href="http://java.net/projects/datafx/pages/UsingMaven">dependency management using Maven</a> when using the DataFX artifacts. He also asks the community for feedback on the preferred way involving JavaFX. I’d like to see Gradle in the picture with transitive dependencies set (sorry couldn’t resist).</li>
	<li><strong>Dan Zwolenski</strong> blogs about <a href="http://www.zenjava.com/2012/03/27/javafx-and-spring-security/">Spring Security and JavaFX</a>. He shows you how to integrate the Spring framework to authenticate and authorize access in a JavaFX application.</li>
	<li>I recently blogged about the creation of a spaceship game using JavaFX 2.x. as <a href="http://carlfx.wordpress.com/2012/03/29/javafx-2-gametutorial-part-1/">Part 1</a> of a series of tutorials which will incrementally take you through the game development process. Here I basically demo the way I want the spaceship to navigate.</li>
	<li><a href="http://griffon.codehaus.org/">The Griffon Framework</a> has now released the <a href="http://artifacts.griffon-framework.org/plugin/javafx">JavaFX plugin</a> which allows writing Griffon JavaFX applications by using <a href="http://groovy.codehaus.org/GroovyFX">GroovyFX</a> to code views. Griffon also has a new <a href="http://artifacts.griffon-framework.org/archetype/javafx">JavaFX archetype</a> to create a simple JavaFX Griffon application in seconds.</li>
	<li><strong>Java-Buddy </strong>(a blogger whose name is still a mystery to me) has created quick and simple tutorials on how-to <a href="http://java-buddy.blogspot.com/2012/03/execute-javascript-in-webview-from-java.html">execute JavaScript in WebView</a> from Java code and how-to <a href="http://java-buddy.blogspot.com/2012/03/embed-google-maps-in-javafx-webview.html">embed Google Maps in JavaFX WebView</a>.</li>
	<li><strong>Anton Epple </strong>blogs about a nice looking JavaFX 2.x version of the popular game <a href="http://88.198.17.44/blog/2012/03/30/programming-games-in-javafx-2-0/">Tetris</a>.&nbsp; I hope to see him make it even better. He mentions about some audio issues. Hopefully he can file the issue on <a href="http://javafx-jira.kenai.com/secure/Dashboard.jspa">Jira</a> so that it can be followed up.</li>
	<li><strong>Wichit Sombat </strong>creates a bunch of videos this week where he walks you through tutorials on How-to <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lDDVivbXdKI">create bouncing icons</a>, a <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7uw0Nzj6A6Q">docking application</a>, <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_B6ciKMPb2g">setting up IntelliJ IDEA for JavaFX</a>, and <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ck6_RamocFU">getting started on JavaFX on Ubuntu</a>.</li>
	<li><strong>Tom Schindl </strong>publishes his slide presentation on e(fx)clipse, the <a href="http://tomsondev.bestsolution.at/2012/03/28/slides-from-eclipsecon-talks/">Eclipse Tooling and Runtime for JavaFX</a>.</li>
	<li><strong>Dilip </strong>has a very cool blog entry and tutorial that will help you <a href="http://thisiswhatiknowabout.blogspot.com/2011/11/hello-world-jbox2d-with-javafx-20.html">get started with JavaFX</a> with <a href="http://www.jbox2d.org/">JBox2D</a> (the very cool physics library).</li>
</ul>
<h4>Swing</h4>
<ul>
	<li><strong>Jide Software</strong> had a <a href="http://www.jidesoft.com/history/">release</a> on March 27, 2012 – version 3.3.7. This release included many enhancements and bug fixes.</li>
</ul>
<h4>Miscellaneous</h4>
<ul>
	<li><strong>Scott Kovatch</strong> blogs about the project <a href="http://skovatch.wordpress.com/2012/03/30/app-bundler-project-now-open/">App bundler</a> project at <a href="http://java.net/projects/appbundler">Java.net</a>. Also, Java Champion <strong>Joshua Marinacci</strong> offered to <a href="http://joshondesign.com/2012/02/26/AppBundler_new_project">donate code</a> to Scott’s project.</li>
</ul>
<p>That’s it for this week everyone. Keep up the great work and keep those creative juices flowing!</p>
]]></Content>
	</post>
