<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<post>
		<ID>93</ID>
		<Slug>graduation</Slug>
		<Title>Graduation</Title>
		<Date>2007-05-20</Date>
		<Status>publish</Status>
		<Categories>Life|Miscellaneous</Categories>
		<Tags/>
		<Content><![CDATA[<p>Well, this past week I graduated, so it's time to chuck up a few photos. Click on them for bigger versions.</p>

<p>I'm now an official software engineer, having graduated with a Bachelor of Engineering Honours in Software Engineering. I was also awarded First-Class Honours, and the title of Massey Scholar (which was received by only four engineers, and is awarded to the top 5% at Massey for each college).</p>

<p>Fortunately Palmy's weather was ok - there was only the threat of rain (as is the case any day of the year really!). Walking out of the Regent where the graduation was held was a bit of a shock - a fairly cold wind had set in which resulted in our balloons becoming rather lethal weapons to anyone unfortunate to be down-wind).</p>

<p>Now for the photos:</p>

<p><a href="/content/2007/05/img_1916.JPG" title="img_1916.JPG"><img src="/content/2007/05/img_1916.thumbnail.JPG" alt="img_1916.JPG"></a></p>

<p>This photo is taken at the entrance to Massey at about 8:00am - we headed out there early before the crowds and got a heap of photos.</p>

<p><a href="/content/2007/05/img_1998.JPG" title="img_1998.JPG"><img src="/content/2007/05/img_1998.thumbnail.JPG" alt="img_1998.JPG" height="99" width="131"></a></p>

<p>This photo was taken in the Esplanade in Palmy. It's the same place <a href="http://www.juliagiles.com">Julia</a> and I got some of our wedding photos taken, and so seeing as we had some free time, we come here to take some photos.</p>

<p><a href="/content/2007/05/img_2086.JPG" title="img_2086.JPG"><img src="/content/2007/05/img_2086.thumbnail.JPG" alt="img_2086.JPG"></a></p>

<p>This is me with my supervisor of my research last year on software plugins and this year on the semantic web.</p>
]]></Content>
	</post>
