<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<post>
		<ID>881</ID>
		<Slug>java-desktop-links-of-the-week-august-16</Slug>
		<Title>Java desktop links of the week, August 16</Title>
		<Date>2010-08-15</Date>
		<Status>publish</Status>
		<Categories><![CDATA[Programming>Java>Java Client]]></Categories>
		<Tags>javafx|swing</Tags>
		<Content><![CDATA[<p>A big week in the Java world, and I'm going to completely side-step the elephant in the room in todays post. This week there has been a great number of Java desktop posts, so I am very pleased to be presenting these links to you today. Enjoy! :-)</p>
<h4>Swing</h4>
<ul>
	<li><strong>Kirill Grouchnikov</strong> has published the final releases of <a href="http://www.pushing-pixels.org/?p=2153">Trident 1.3, Flamingo 5.0, Substance 6.1 and the Substance Flamingo Plugin 6.1</a>. People using older versions are encouraged to upgrade as these releases contain bug fixes and new features.</li>
	<li><span class="fn"><strong>Gerrit Grunwald</strong> has finally stopped teasing us with screenshots of his Swing gauge library, and <a href="http://harmoniccode.blogspot.com/2010/08/java-swing-component-library.html">has released them as a jar file</a> to include in your applications. It appears <span style="text-decoration: line-through;">that source code is not currently available, and the license is also unclear, so proceed with caution</span> you can download the source code from the <a href="http://kenai.com/projects/steelseries">Kenai project site</a>, where it is BSD licensed.
</span></li>
	<li><strong>Jacek Furmankiewicz</strong> has announced the <a href="http://jacekfurmankiewicz.blogspot.com/2010/08/swing-javabuilder-10-is-out.html">1.0 release of Swing JavaBuilder</a>. Swing JavaBuilder is  a library aiming to maximise the productivity of Java Swing developers via declarative UIs, MigLayout, DSL, databinding and built-in input validation.</li>
	<li><span class="post-author vcard"><span class="fn"><strong>Kas Thomas</strong> has written about <a href="http://asserttrue.blogspot.com/2010/08/smart-sobel-image-filter.html">creating a "Smart Sobel" image filter</a>.</span></span></li>
	<li><span class="post-author vcard"><span class="fn">It seems like there is still life left in the Swing component market, with a <a href="http://www.javaswingcomponents.com/">new company entering the scene</a>. Currently they offer Accordion, wrapping label and analog clock components.</span></span></li>
	<li><span class="post-author vcard"><span class="fn"><strong>Michael Schnell</strong> wrote in to say that a </span></span><a href="http://www.fuin.org/kickstart4j/index.html">new version of the webstart based installer "Kickstart4J" is available</a>. Kickstart4J is a Java Webstart based installer and updater. You can <a href="http://javadeveloperslife.wordpress.com/2009/05/28/a-better-java-webstart-for-standalone-applications/">find more information here</a>.</li>
</ul>
<h4>JavaFX</h4>
<ul>
	<li><strong>Eric Bruno</strong> has posted an article over at Dr Dobbs about building custom controls in JavaFX, in particular a <a href="http://www.drdobbs.com/java/226600252">ListView control that supports multiple selection</a>. Remember that recently FX Experience also posted an example on <a href="http://fxexperience.com/2010/07/listview-multiple-selection/">how to create a multiple selection ListView</a>.</li>
	<li><strong>Martijn van de Rijdt</strong> has written about <a href="http://java.sogeti.nl/JavaBlog/2010/08/14/javafx-maven/">building a JavaFX project with Maven</a> using javaFX 1.3 and the <a href="http://wiki.jfrog.org/confluence/display/JP/JavaFX+Compiler+Maven+Plugin">JFrog JavaFX Compiler Maven Plugin</a>.</li>
	<li><strong>itssmee</strong> has blogged about <a href="http://itssmee.wordpress.com/2010/08/12/trying-to-replicate-processings-house-of-cards-code-in-javafx/">recreating Radioheads 'House of Cards' music video in JavaFX</a> (the original video was created in Processing). For those unsure what is being referred to, <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8nTFjVm9sTQ">check out this YouTube video</a>.</li>
	<li><strong>Sergey Malenkov</strong> has blogged about <a href="https://malenkov.dev.java.net/20100813/">multi-threading in JavaFX</a>, by recreating Reversi.</li>
	<li><strong>Abhilshit Soni</strong> has posted '<a href="http://dukesrepaint.blogspot.com/2010/05/yet-another-javafx-app.html">Yet another JavaFX App</a>', which includes a runnable demo and source code.</li>
</ul>
<h4>Miscellaneous</h4>
<ul>
	<li><strong>Josh Marinacci</strong> has announced his project <a href="http://leonardosketch.org/">Leonardo</a>, which is "an open source vector drawing program for the 21st century. It focuses  on common tasks like mockups, sketches, and presentations with a clean  and consistent user interface. It is designed to be augmented by  internet webservices and plugins created in several scripting languages." Leonardo is written in Java, but does not use Swing or JavaFX, and as far as I can see, is just using custom components written by Josh.</li>
</ul>
<p>That's that for another week. I hope you all found something useful in the links today, and thanks to everyone for emailing their links to me. Catch you all in a weeks time :-)</p>
<p><div id="_mcePaste" style="position: absolute; left: -10000px; top: 0px; width: 1px; height: 1px; overflow: hidden;"><span class="fn">Gerrit Grunwald</span></div></p>
]]></Content>
	</post>
