<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<post>
		<ID>1813</ID>
		<Slug>java-desktop-links-of-the-past-few-weeks-october-13</Slug>
		<Title>Java desktop links of the (past few) week(s), October 13</Title>
		<Date>2014-10-12</Date>
		<Status>publish</Status>
		<Categories><![CDATA[Programming>Java>Java Client]]></Categories>
		<Tags>javafx</Tags>
		<Content><![CDATA[<p>Sorry for the few weeks of radio silence - I had the JavaOne distraction followed by a week of catching up on everything that needed me during the JavaOne week. I'm only just surfacing again now, and there are a huge number of links to cover, so pardon the succinctness - we have a lot to get through! I'll also note that I've bound to have missed some links, so apologies for that. Now, on to the links - enjoy :-)</p>
<h4>JavaFX</h4>
<ul>
	<li>Soon the JavaFX sessions will have their audio and slides posted to Parleys, but until then the slides are available for download from the JavaOne site - just <a href="https://oracleus.activeevents.com/2014/connect/search.ww?eventRef=javaone#loadSearch-event=null&amp;searchPhrase=&amp;searchType=session&amp;tc=0&amp;sortBy=&amp;p=&amp;i%2810009%29=10111">search the content catalog</a>. I'll post my slides sometime along with further commentary about the session, but until then, you can find the slides for my sessions here: <a href="https://oracleus.activeevents.com/2014/connect/sessionDetail.ww?SESSION_ID=3064">custom JavaFX controls</a>, <a href="https://oracleus.activeevents.com/2014/connect/sessionDetail.ww?SESSION_ID=3066">Scenic View</a>, <a href="https://oracleus.activeevents.com/2014/connect/sessionDetail.ww?SESSION_ID=2079">ControlsFX</a>, and <a href="https://oracleus.activeevents.com/2014/connect/sessionDetail.ww?SESSION_ID=3640">DataFX</a>.</li>
	<li>During JavaOne I announced the release of two projects: <a href="http://fxexperience.com/2014/09/announcing-scenic-view-8-0-0/">Scenic View 8.0.0</a> and <a href="http://fxexperience.com/2014/09/announcing-controlsfx-8-20-7/">ControlsFX 8.20.7</a>. These are both major releases with a bunch of new functionality and bug fixes, so get downloading!</li>
	<li><strong>Johan Vos</strong> made a big splash at JavaOne this year. Firstly, he <a href="http://www.lodgon.com/dali/blog/entry/JavaFXPorts_winner_of_Dukes_Choice_Award">won a Dukes Choice award</a> for his <a href="http://javafxports.org/">JavaFX port to Android</a>. Secondly, he has an article up in Java Magazine that covers how to use this port to <a href="http://www.oraclejavamagazine-digital.com/javamagazine_open/20140910?pg=56#pg56">write a JavaFX application that runs on Android</a>. Thirdly, it was announced at JavaOne that the JavaFX ports project will be working to make Java 8 (and therefore JavaFX 8) available on both Android and iOS devices. I'll be posting an interview with <strong>Johan</strong> and <strong>Niklas</strong> in the coming week.</li>
	<li><strong>Hendrik Ebbers</strong> has a bunch of blog posts, including on the topics of '<a href="http://www.guigarage.com/2014/10/javaone-2014-slides/">JavaOne 2014 Slides</a>', '<a href="http://www.guigarage.com/2014/10/iconify-application-resolution-independent-way/">Iconify your application the resolution independent way</a>', '<a href="http://www.guigarage.com/2014/10/dialog-objects-pattern-automated-tests-testfx/">The View Objects Pattern &amp; automated tests with TestFX</a>', '<a href="http://www.guigarage.com/2014/10/integrate-custom-fonts-javafx-application-using-css/">How to integrate custom fonts in your JavaFX application by using CSS</a>', and '<a href="http://www.guigarage.com/2014/09/enrich-list-ui-using-medialistcell/">Enrich your List UI by using the MediaListCell</a>'.</li>
	<li><strong>Hendrik Ebbers</strong> has also <a href="http://www.guigarage.com/2014/09/datafx-8/">posted the slides</a> that he, Johan Vos, and I presented at JavaOne regarding the DataFX project.</li>
	<li><strong>Tomas Mikula</strong> has created another JavaFX-related library, this time called <a href="https://github.com/TomasMikula/WellBehavedFX">WellBehavedFX</a>, which consists of 'composable event handlers and skin scaffolding for JavaFX controls'.</li>
	<li><strong>Tom Schindl</strong> has a post about <a href="http://tomsondev.bestsolution.at/2014/10/01/e4-on-javafx-and-opendolphin/">e4 on JavaFX and OpenDolphin</a>.</li>
	<li><strong>Rob Terpilowski</strong> has posted a <a href="http://rterp.wordpress.com/2014/09/29/make-money-online-automatically-trading-commodities-with-javafx-and-the-netbeans-rich-client-platform/">few screenshots and a video of the Zoi Capital ZQ Trader software</a> written in JavaFX.</li>
	<li><strong>Sébastien Bordes</strong> has announced the release of <a href="http://blog.jrebirth.org/releases/jrebirth-application-framework-7-7-4-is-released/">JRebirth Application Framework 7.7.4</a>.</li>
	<li><strong>Dirk Lemmermann</strong> has been very busy with his (commercial) FlexGanttFX library. Firstly, he has <a href="http://dlemmermann.wordpress.com/2014/09/20/flexganttfx-first-javafx-component-on-componentsource/">published it for sale on ComponentSource</a> (as he states, for those unfamiliar with ComponentSource, it is an international reseller of software components, basically the “App Store” of custom controls). Secondly, he has <a href="http://flexganttfx.com/download.html">released version 1.1.0</a> which includes a number of new features and bug fixes. Thirdly, he has been working hard on <a href="https://flexgantt.atlassian.net/wiki/pages/viewpage.action?pageId=491528">writing high quality documentation</a> for the control.</li>
	<li><strong>Andres Almiray</strong> has posted that "<a href="http://jroller.com/aalmiray/entry/it_s_time_for_a">It's time for a Desktop Application Framework JSR</a>". If you are interested in being involved, be sure to get in touch with him.</li>
	<li>The <strong>dooApp</strong> blog has two posts. Firstly, they've posted details about how they've <a href="http://blog.dooapp.com/2014/09/fxform2-sampler.html">created a sampler application</a> based on the ControlsFX FXSampler component. Secondly, they have a post on '<a href="http://blog.dooapp.com/2014/10/javafx-persistence-made-easy-with.html">JavaFX persistence made easy with JCROMfx</a>'.</li>
	<li><strong>Carlos Martins</strong> has posted about how to developed a <a href="http://makeitmartins.blogspot.co.nz/2014/10/javafx2-websocket-client-deployed-by.html?spref=tw">JavaFX websocket client application that is deployed via Webstart JNLP</a>.</li>
	<li><strong>Christian Schudt</strong> has posted about Babbler - an XMPP library for Java - and more specifically, a <a href="http://babbler-xmpp.blogspot.de/2014/10/visual-xmpp-view-coming-in-next-release.html">visual XMPP viewer coming in the next release</a>.</li>
	<li><strong>Mik Arber</strong> has created a new JavaFX layout container he calls <a href="http://miksblog.capcaval.org/2014/10/javafx-layout/">RefPoint</a>. He states in the post that "it’s principal is simple as you define one node position or two points node relatively to some reference points."</li>
</ul>
<p>Phew! That took a while to write out! I hope you enjoyed the links from the past few weeks - and I'll catch you again next week! :-)</p>
]]></Content>
	</post>
