<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<post>
		<ID>1120</ID>
		<Slug>java-desktop-links-of-the-week-october-24</Slug>
		<Title>Java desktop links of the week, October 24</Title>
		<Date>2011-10-24</Date>
		<Status>publish</Status>
		<Categories><![CDATA[Programming>Java>Java Client]]></Categories>
		<Tags>griffon|javafx|swing</Tags>
		<Content><![CDATA[<p>Having been traveling for the last three weeks, I've not been able to post the weekly Java desktop links roundup. Today I'm trying to make up for this by posting all the links I gathered as I was traveling (and on vacation). There are two problems with this approach: 1) what follows is basically information overload, and 2) I almost certainly missed links. I hope you can all forgive me for this one time, and I also hope you find a heap of interesting links in this post (it took me a looonnggg time to write this week!).</p>

<p>Whilst I'm here, I must note that it was great meeting so many people at JavaOne. The number of times I was speaking to someone who didn't know me, only to see my name badge and know exactly who I was because of this blog was actually very impressive. I'm surprised so many of you read this blog! Anyway, with that (and because this post is already long enough) let's get straight into it... :-)</p>
<h4>JavaFX</h4>
<ul>
	<li>The big news out of JavaOne for JavaFX was the <a href="http://fxexperience.com/2011/10/javafx-2-0-released/">general availability release of JavaFX 2.0</a> for Windows, and the beta release of JavaFX 2.0 for Mac OS X. A number of sites posted <a href="http://drdobbs.com/blogs/java/231900029">articles</a> <a href="http://www.zdnet.co.uk/news/application-development/2011/10/06/javafx-20-arrives-and-heads-for-open-source-40094121/">relevant</a> to this.</li>
	<li>Following hot on the heels of the JavaFX 2.0 release is <a href="http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/java/javafx/downloads/index.html">JavaFX 2.0.1</a>, which is a security-only update released in-sync with <a href="http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/topics/security/javacpuoct2011-443431.html">all other Java security updates</a> (which explains why it was released so soon after 2.0).</li>
	<li>We've also put out <a href="http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/java/javafx/downloads/javafx2-macosx-487281.html">another build of JavaFX 2.0 beta for Mac OS X</a>, taking the build number up to version 5.</li>
	<li>My partners in crime over at FX Experience, <strong>Richard Bair</strong> and <strong>Jasper Potts</strong>, have been busily blogging over at FX Experience, including posts titled "<a href="http://fxexperience.com/2011/10/dont-use-impl/">Don't use impl!</a>", "<a href="http://fxexperience.com/2011/10/javafx-technical-keynote-at-javaone-video/">JavaFX Technical Keynote at JavaOne Video</a>", "<a href="http://fxexperience.com/2011/10/javafx-sessions-at-javaone-2011-online/">JavaFX sessions at JavaOne 2011 online</a>", "<a href="http://fxexperience.com/2011/10/fxml-why-it-rocks-and-the-next-phase/">FXML: Why It Rocks, And The Next Phase</a>", and "<a href="http://fxexperience.com/2011/10/correctly-checking-keyevents/">Correctly Checking KeyEvents</a>".</li>
	<li>A number of blogs have appeared online related to JavaFX FXML being used in conjunction with dependency injection frameworks. Firstly, <strong>Tom Schindl</strong> has blogged about <a href="http://tomsondev.bestsolution.at/2011/10/07/fxml-and-google-guice/">JavaFX FXML and Google Guice</a>. Following this, <strong>Richard Bair</strong> blogged <a href="http://fxexperience.com/2011/10/fxml-guice/">about exactly the same topic</a>. Finally, <strong>Zonski</strong> has blogged about <a href="http://www.zenjava.com/2011/10/23/javafx-2-0-fxml-and-spring/">JavaFX FXML and Spring</a>, and in a separate post, '<a href="http://www.zenjava.com/2011/10/23/better-controller-injection/">better controller injection</a>'.</li>
	<li>Speaking of <strong>Jasper</strong>, he was <a href="http://blogs.oracle.com/javaspotlight/entry/java_spotlight_episode_50_jasper">recently interviewed</a> by the <strong>Java Spotlight podcast</strong> regarding the JavaFX 2.0 release.</li>
	<li>The <strong>Oracle Media Network</strong> has five videos related to JavaFX 2.0 features: <a href="http://medianetwork.oracle.com/video/player/1193110450001">graphics</a>, <a href="http://medianetwork.oracle.com/video/player/1193176129001">UI controls</a>, <a href="http://medianetwork.oracle.com/video/player/1193110454001">animation</a>, <a href="http://medianetwork.oracle.com/video/player/1193110451001">effects</a>, and <a href="http://medianetwork.oracle.com/video/player/1193176134001">embedding web content</a>.</li>
	<li><strong>Tom Schindl</strong> has also been very busy on his e(fx)clipse project, <a href="http://tomsondev.bestsolution.at/2011/10/17/efxclipse-0-0-7-released/">putting out version 0.0.7</a>, which includes a number of new features, including new wizards, live preview support for editing his 'FXGraph' DSL, auto-completion of FXGraph, support for dependency injection, and the start of an application framework.</li>
	<li><strong>Mr LoNee</strong> has blogged about a similar feature as mentioned above - a '<a href="http://www.mrlonee.com/?p=333">NodeCodeEditor</a>' that live previews what is happening as code is being edited (although there are constraints, so be sure to read the blog post completely).</li>
	<li><strong>Jide Software</strong> has released a free-to-use <a href="http://www.jidesoft.com/blog/2011/10/04/meet-our-first-javafx-component/">JavaFX RangeSlider control</a> (that is, a Slider that has two thumbs rather than one). All I can say is keep up the great work! I want to see a thriving 3rd party controls ecosystem in JavaFX! :-)</li>
	<li>At JavaOne we demonstrated JavaFX running on various tablet devices. Whilst this is not in any public roadmaps yet, there have been a <a href="http://www.infoworld.com/d/application-development/oracle-shows-javafx-ios-and-android-174996">few</a> <a href="http://www.infoworld.com/d/application-development/oracles-ambitious-plan-client-side-java-175241">writeups</a> on this <a href="http://www.computerworld.com/s/article/9220535/Oracle_shows_JavaFX_on_iOS_and_Android">demonstration</a> that may be of interest.</li>
	<li>Another big JavaOne announcement was the plan to <a href="http://blogs.oracle.com/javaone/entry/javafx_2_0_arrives_and">open source the entire JavaFX stack</a> through the OpenJDK.</li>
	<li>One of the talks I gave at JavaOne (along with <strong>Johan Vos</strong>) was about our <a href="http://www.javafxdata.org">DataFX project</a>, related to simplifying the population and rendering of ListView/TreeView/TableView controls. Just today I did a better <a href="http://fxexperience.com/2011/10/introduction-to-datafx/">write-up explaining what the project is</a>, and (hopefully) enticing more people to play around with it.</li>
	<li>All <a href="http://fxexperience.com/2011/10/slides-from-javaone/">JavaOne slides appear to be online for public consumption</a>. I posted a blog post that links to the three talks I gave, as well as a link to the content catalog where you may download all other slide decks.</li>
	<li><strong>Roman Kennke</strong> has posted about "<a href="http://rkennke.wordpress.com/2011/10/11/javafx-2-the-new-swing/">JavaFX 2 — The new Swing ?&nbsp;(!)</a>".</li>
	<li><strong>Bertrand Goetzmann</strong> <a href="https://twitter.com/#%21/bgoetzmann/statuses/126407814783574016">has updated his Grezi application</a> with JavaFX 2.0 GA support, and now uses the latest GroovyFX release. He has put up a video that <a href="http://www.screenr.com/ZAOs">demonstrates the HTML 5 slideshows feature</a>.</li>
	<li><strong>Patrick Webster</strong> has <a href="http://patrickwebster.blogspot.com/2011/10/pac-man-in-javafx-2.html">ported a Pac-Man clone</a> that was originally written for JavaFX 1.3.1 to use the new JavaFX 2.0 release.</li>
	<li><strong>Dustin</strong> has blogged about the NetBeans 7.1 beta, and how it can be <a href="http://marxsoftware.blogspot.com/2011/10/hello-javafx-20-introduction-by.html">used for developing JavaFX 2.0 applications</a>.</li>
	<li><strong>Hamilton Matos</strong> has blogged about '<a href="http://www.jsfcentral.com/articles/jsf_and_javafx.html">Building JSF 2.0 Composite Components Based on JavaFX with NetBeans</a>'.</li>
	<li><strong>Gail Anderson</strong> has two new JavaFX 2.0 blog posts online, both about animation and binding. The first post creates a <a href="http://www.asgteach.com/blog/?p=113">simple countdown timer</a>, whilst the second post extends the first by <a href="http://www.asgteach.com/blog/?p=219">adding a progress bar into the mix</a>.</li>
</ul>
<h4>Swing</h4>
<ul>
	<li><strong>Gerrit Grunwald</strong> (of SteelSeries fame) spoke at JavaOne about building custom components. Unfortunately I could not attend, but as I mentioned above, all slides are now online, and <a href="https://oracleus.wingateweb.com/published/oracleus2011/sessions/23240/S23240_144217.pdf">his slides can be found here</a>.</li>
	<li><strong>Jide Software</strong> released <a href="http://www.jidesoft.com/history/">version 3.2.4 of their Swing libraries</a>.</li>
</ul>
<h4>Miscellaneous</h4>
<ul>
	<li><a href="http://groovy.dzone.com/announcements/griffon-094-released">Griffon 0.9.4 has been released</a>. This release includes a number of new features, bug fixes, and breaking changes.</li>
	<li><strong>Laurent Caron</strong> has put out a <a href="http://code.google.com/a/eclipselabs.org/p/opal/">new release of his Opal project</a>, an umbrella project for a number of SWT widgets. This release includes four new components, including a Header widget, a Titled Separator widget, LoginDialog and a Tip of the Day window.</li>
</ul>
<p>Phew! That's that for another week. I'll get back into the regular schedule starting next week, so hopefully next weeks posting won't be as great an ordeal (for you and me!) next week. Catch you all in a weeks time folks :-)</p>
]]></Content>
	</post>
