<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<post>
		<ID>53</ID>
		<Slug>microsoft-presentation-and-t-cosy</Slug>
		<Title>Microsoft presentation and T-COSY</Title>
		<Date>2006-03-05</Date>
		<Status>publish</Status>
		<Categories>Life</Categories>
		<Tags>ms-student-ambassador</Tags>
		<Content><![CDATA[<p><span id="BlogViewId"></p>
<p><div id="msgcns!9C7F360F305C1AA0!205"></p>
<p><div>Hey there,</div></p>
<p><div>My name is Jonathan Giles. Some of you may know me: I'm a fourth year software engineering student at</div></p>
<p><div>Massey. This year I'm doing a bit of work representing Microsoft around campus, so you'll probably hear</div></p>
<p><div>from me a bit. Basically I get to know about Microsoft technologies, and plan to help anyone out there</div></p>
<p><div>to get the most out of this stuff.</div></p>
<p><div></div></p>
<p><div>I'll probably give a few presentations, but I'd rather get behind things like T-COSY and helping to get people enthused about Microsoft stuff, whether it's the Xbox 360 or the latest Visual Studio. To this end, specifically for those people involved with T-COSY, I plan on getting a few prizes to hand out over the year, as judged by the organisers of the event. For the upcoming LAN</div></p>
<p><div>on March 11th, I should have some gamesÂ&nbsp;and copies of Microsoft Office, plus various Xbox 360 goodies to</div></p>
<p><div>tide you over until the 23rd (The 360's launch day).</div></p>
<p><div></div></p>
<p><div>Also, in relation to the 360, I've got a way you could win one, as well as heaps of other cool prizes.</div></p>
<p><div>Firstly, there are two Microsoft presentations coming up on March 16th and 17th. The times and places</div></p>
<p><div>are yet to be announced, but they will be the same in content - so just come to whichever you can make</div></p>
<p><div>it to. I'll get posters out overÂ&nbsp;campus shortly, but otherwise check out my blog here:</div></p>
<p><a href="http://spaces.msn.com/JoGiles">http://spaces.msn.com/JoGiles</a></p>
<p><div>I keep this page updated with the latest news about all things Microsoft and Massey.</div></p>
<p><div></div></p>
<p><div>On the 16th and 17th you'll learn about ways Microsoft can help you out at Massey through the Academic Alliance, etc, and also how you can win those prizes I keep mentioning.</div></p>
<p><div>But because the draw closes on the 17th, heres how to enter: sign up for the MSDN Connection newsletter</div></p>
<p><div>here, and say you're from Massey University:</p>
<p><a href="http://www.microsoft.com/nz/msdn/connection/default.mspx">http://www.microsoft.com/nz/msdn/connection/default.mspx</a></div></p>
<p><div>That'll get you entered into the draw. Trust me, the prizes are well worth it. They include:</p>
<p>* XBOX 360</p>
<p>* 17" and 19" Philips LCD Screens</p>
<p>* Philips Digital Photo Frames</p>
<p>* Navman Navigation System</p>
<p>* Microsoft Office Professional 2003</p>
<p>* Microsoft Office OneNote 2003</p>
<p>* Microsoft Windows XP Professional</p>
<p>* Microsoft Digital Image Suite 2006</p>
<p>* Age of Empires 3</p>
<p>* Microsoft Freebies Pack (assorted goodies to get you going)</div></p>
<p><div></div></p>
<p><div>Now, to steal from a fellow ambassadors blog:</p>
<p>Heard of the MSDN Academic Alliance? It's a programme Microsoft runs worldwide for universities (and</div></p>
<p><div>polytechnics) to give IT-related students access to an absolutely massive range of software, completely</div></p>
<p><div>free of charge. This includes Windows XP, all the Windows Server System products (such as Windows</div></p>
<p><div>Server, SQL Server, BizTalk Server...), Visual Studio, Visio and heaps more. It doesn't include games or</div></p>
<p><div>Microsoft Office (or anything XBox-related!) but there are separate promotions for those.</div></p>
<p><div></div></p>
<p><div>So, see you on the 11th, and hopefully on either the 16th or 17th. Feel free to ask me any questions.</p>
<p>Cheers,</p>
<p>Jonathan Giles</div></p>
<p></div></p>
<p></span></p>
]]></Content>
	</post>
