<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<post>
		<ID>2176</ID>
		<Slug>exciting-news</Slug>
		<Title>Exciting News</Title>
		<Date>2016-09-26</Date>
		<Status>publish</Status>
		<Categories>Life</Categories>
		<Tags/>
		<Content><![CDATA[<p>It is with incredible relief and excitement that Julia and I can announce that we are expecting our second child in early February, 2017. Today we are at the 20.3 weeks mark, and with that we feel safe enough to share this publicly. From our latest ultrasound, signs are pointing to there being a good chance that our next child to join our son Henry will be a little girl. Henry is such a cool dude, and we can't wait to get to know our daughter in only a few months time.</p>

<p>With this excitement flows other emotions too. Miscarriage is something that is rarely talked&nbsp;about, and it was with considerable sadness that we struggled through three separate miscarriages in an incredibly short period of time. You begin to dread going to ultrasound appointments (where they used to be exciting when we were naive with Henry) - fearing some morsel of bad news. Every time the bad news hit us like a tonne of bricks, bringing with it sadness and disappointment about losing something you desperately want. In that instant it feels like the child has gone from being real to an apparition - a figment containing our hopes, excitement, and future, that never quite was. You reset your dreams once more, and hope like hell it'll never happen again, and then, you are back at square one.</p>

<p>To others that struggle through this, we have no words of wisdom or advice. Nothing can quite heal the struggle you must go through, and the sadness you must endure. All you are ever given is statistics, and rarely do these make the situation better. All that can be said is to see the positives as best you can, and don't give up.</p>

<p>And now, the obligatory photo:</p>

<p><a href="/content/2016/09/baby2.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-2177" src="/content/2016/09/baby2-1024x646.jpg" alt="baby 2" width="497" height="317"></a></p>
]]></Content>
	</post>
