<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<post>
		<ID>1066</ID>
		<Slug>java-desktop-links-of-the-week-june-27</Slug>
		<Title>Java desktop links of the week, June 27</Title>
		<Date>2011-06-27</Date>
		<Status>publish</Status>
		<Categories><![CDATA[Programming>Java>Java Client]]></Categories>
		<Tags>griffon|javafx|swing</Tags>
		<Content><![CDATA[<p>Here we go again, with this weeks batch of links. Thanks to the people <a href="mailto:jonathan@jonathangiles.net">contacting me</a> with links and praise - it's all much appreciated :-) Let's get into things...</p>
<h4>JavaFX</h4>
<ul>
	<li>There is an Oracle webcast coming up on the 30th of June that is titled '<a href="https://event.on24.com/eventRegistration/EventLobbyServlet?target=registration.jsp&amp;eventid=317504&amp;sessionid=1&amp;key=2BDA9E88948C061595065A98190546F1&amp;partnerref=JavaFX2.0PR&amp;sf1692579=1&amp;sourcepage=register">The Code of Enterprise Success Begins with JavaFX 2.0</a>'. It features <strong>Jai Suri</strong> and <strong>Jasper Potts</strong> talking about JavaFX 2.0, and might include some interesting news and demonstrations.</li>
	<li><strong>Tom Schindl</strong> has <a href="http://tomsondev.bestsolution.at/2011/06/24/introducing-efxclipse/">announced e(fx)clipse</a>. The 0.0.1 release is minimal but no doubt useful for JavaFX 2.0 developers choosing to use Eclipse: it introduces a CSS editor that supports the JavaFX -fx extensions.</li>
	<li><strong>Jim Connor</strong> has blogged about <a href="http://blogs.oracle.com/jtc/entry/observations_in_migrating_from_javafx">translating a JavaFX Script application to JavaFX 2.0</a>.</li>
	<li><strong>Stephen Chin</strong> continues to present the '<a href="http://www.slideshare.net/steveonjava/javafx-20-with-alternative-languages-groovy-clojure-scala-fantom-and-visage-8395594">JavaFX 2.0 With Alternative Languages</a>' talk at conferences. He has just posted the slides for his talk at Jazoon, where he covers using JavaFX 2.0 with Groovy, Clojure, Scala, Fantom and Visage.</li>
	<li>Speaking of alternate languages, probably the one leading the pack is the GroovyFX project, which obviously provides improved Groovy support. They've just put up a <a href="http://docs.codehaus.org/display/GROOVY/GroovyFX">heap of documentation</a> that demonstrates how to use the JavaFX APIs using GroovyFX - be sure to check it out!</li>
	<li><strong>Artem Ananiev</strong> has covered <a href="http://weblogs.java.net/blog/ixmal/archive/2011/06/23/javafx-20-how-size-your-windows-easily">how to size your windows in JavaFX 2.0 easily</a>.</li>
	<li><strong>Seyhan Basmaci</strong> has blogged about <a href="http://seyhanbasmaci.blogspot.com/2011/06/javafx-20-beta-sample-application.html">building a JavaFX 2.0 sample application</a>, which features a login form as well as a TableView, communicating with a remote server.</li>
	<li><strong>jojorabbit4</strong> has blogged about <a href="http://jojorabbitjavafxblog.wordpress.com/2011/06/23/javafx-2-0-custom-combobox/">creating a custom JavaFX 2.0 ComboBox control</a>. For what it's worth, I spent a few hours this past weekend creating one as well, which may turn up somewhere sometime soon. I even posted an <a href="/content/2011/06/comboBox.png">image</a> or <a href="/content/2011/06/comboBox2.png">two</a> to tease its current state (which is: unfinished, but much better than nothing).</li>
	<li><strong>Laurent Nicolas</strong> has blogged about <a href="http://www.mrlonee.com/?p=237">creating a simple JavaFX 2.0 slide presenter</a>.</li>
	<li><strong>Narayan</strong> has written about <a href="http://blog.ngopal.com.np/?p=838">masking in JavaFX 2.0</a>.</li>
</ul>
<h4>Swing</h4>
<ul>
	<li><strong>Geertjan Wielenga</strong> has two blog posts covering <a href="http://blogs.oracle.com/geertjan/entry/jgridview">integrating JGrid</a><a href="http://blogs.oracle.com/geertjan/entry/jgridview_part_2">with NetBeans</a>.</li>
	<li><strong>Penkov Vladimir</strong> has blogged about <a href="http://penkovvladimir.blogspot.com/2011/06/wizard-with-swinghtmltemplate.html">using the swinghtmltemplate project to create wizards</a>.</li>
</ul>
<h4>Griffon</h4>
<ul>
	<li><strong>Mario</strong> has blogged about a <a href="http://desmontandojava.blogspot.com/2011/06/griffons-tiny-music-player.html">Griffon-based media player</a> user interface he created in very few lines of code.</li>
</ul>
<p>That's all for this weeks folks. Keep up the blogging and exploring of the Java desktop APIs. Catch you in a weeks time! :-)</p>
]]></Content>
	</post>
